A Guide to the Office of the Messrs. Rockefeller records, Friends and Services, Series H FA317
Rockefeller Archive Center
- Friends and Relations
  - Friends and Relations - King, W. L. MacKenzie - Letters Made for Biography, 1915-1917; Folder 1 of 2 (Box 72, Folder 555)
  - Friends and Relations - King, W. L. MacKenzie - Letters Made for Biography, 1914-1941; Folder 2 of 2 (Box 72, Folder 556)
  - Friends and Relations - King, W. L. MacKenzie, 1937-1948; Folder 6 of 9 (Box 72, Folder 557)
  - Friends and Relations - King, W. L. MacKenzie, 1937-1946; Folder 7 of 9 (Box 72, Folder 558)
  - Friends and Relations - King, W. L. MacKenzie, 1938-1944; Folder 7 of 9 (Box 72, Folder 0558A)
  - Friends and Relations - King, W. L. MacKenzie, 1949-1950; Folder 8 of 9 (Box 73, Folder 559)
  - Friends and Relations - King, W. L. MacKenzie, 1950; Folder 8 of 9 (Box 73, Folder 0559A)
  - Friends and Relations - King, W. L. MacKenzie, 1943-1961; Folder 9 of 9 (Box 73, Folder 560)
  - Friends and Relations - King, W. L. MacKenzie, 1950; Folder 9 of 9 (Box 73, Folder 0560A)
  - Friends and Relations - Kirkland, Mr. and Mrs. H., 1914-1934; Folder 1 of 2 (Box 73, Folder 561)
    Mrs. Kirkland was childhood friend of John D. Rockefeller, Jr. and Alta Rockefeller; their financial aid to her and her children.
    108K61
  - Friends and Relations - Kirkland, Mr. and Mrs. H., 1935-1942; Folder 2 of 2 (Box 73, Folder 562)
  - Friends and Relations - Kleberg, Robert Jr., 1939-1956 (Box 73, Folder 563)
    Friend of Nelson A. Rockefeller and other members of family.
    108K7
  - Friends and Relations - Komlosy, Ed, 1904-1917 (Box 73, Folder 564)
    Painted portraits of John D. Rockefeller, Sr. from photographs.
    108K71
  - Friends and Relations - Ladd, Mrs. Walter G., 1918-1960 (Box 74, Folder 565)
    Daughter of a John D. Rockefeller, Sr. partner, personal friend of John D. Rockefeller, Jr. and Abby Aldrich Rockefeller.
    108L1
  - Friends and Relations - Ladd, Mrs. Walter G., 1940-1944 (Box 74, Folder 565A)
  - Friends and Relations - Lallerstadt, Frederick, 1924-1935 (Box 74, Folder 566)
    Alcoholic butler, sent to Gould Farm by John D. Rockefeller, Jr.; recovered.
    108L2
  - Friends and Relations - Larcade, Mrs. E., 1930-1958 (Box 74, Folder 567)
    French friend of John D. Rockefeller, Jr.
  - Friends and Relations - Lee, Ivy, 1914-1928; Folder 1 of 9 (Box 74, Folder 568)
    Employed as public relations advisor; printing and distribution arrangements; press release policy. Comments on publications. Lee's death - work continued by his firm, under T. J. Ross. Regarding Manchester's book on family. Copy of 1961 T. J. Ross speech. Routine handling of requests for information on Rockefellers.
    108L3
  - Friends and Relations - Lee, Ivy, 1926-1932; Folder 2 of 9 (Box 74, Folder 569)
  - Friends and Relations - Lee, Ivy, 1932-1935; Folder 3 of 9 (Box 74, Folder 570)
  - Friends and Relations - Lee, Ivy, 1935-1939; Folder 4 of 9 (Box 75, Folder 571)
  - Friends and Relations - Lee, Ivy, 1939; Folder 5 of 9 (Box 75, Folder 572)
  - Friends and Relations - Lee, Ivy - Arrangements in Case of Mr. Rockefeller's Death, 1935 (Box 75, Folder 573)
  - Friends and Relations - Lee, Ivy, 1941-1954; Folder 6 of 9 (Box 75, Folder 574)
  - Friends and Relations - Lee, Ivy, 1952-1959; Folder 7 of 9 (Box 75, Folder 575)
  - Friends and Relations - Lee, Ivy, 1954-1955; Folder 8 of 9 (Box 75, Folder 576)
  - Friends and Relations - Lee, Ivy, 1939-1947; Folder 9 of 9 (Box 75, Folder 577)
  - Friends and Relations - Lee, Ivy, 1947-1952 (Box 76, Folder 578)
  - Friends and Relations - Lee, Ivy, 1958 (Box 76, Folder 579)
  - Friends and Relations - Lee, Ivy, 1958 (Box 76, Folder 580)
  - Friends and Relations - Lee, Ivy, 1958-1959 (Box 76, Folder 581)
  - Friends and Relations - Lee, Ivy, 1955-1956 (Box 76, Folder 582)
  - Friends and Relations - Lee, Ivy, 1956-1957 (Box 77, Folder 583)
  - Friends and Relations - Lee, Ivy - Financial Arrangements, 1932-1952; Folder 1 of 3 (Box 77, Folder 584)
  - Friends and Relations - Lee, Ivy - Financial Arrangements, 1952-1960; Folder 2 of 3 (Box 77, Folder 585)
  - Friends and Relations - Lee, Ivy - Financial Arrangements, 1921; Folder 3 of 3 (Box 77, Folder 586)
  - Friends and Relations - Lee, Ivy, 1959-1974 (Box 77, Folder 587)
  - Friends and Relations - Lee, Ivy - Washington Squirrel Cage - M. A. Bealle, 1948-1956 (Box 77, Folder 588)
  - Friends and Relations - Lewis, L. W., 1913-1960 (Box 77, Folder 589)
    Superintendent at 10 West 54th Street; salary, gifts; John D. Rockefeller, Sr. rented his car.
    108L31
  - Friends and Relations - Lewis, L. W. - Salary and Gifts, 1920-1951 (Box 78, Folder 590)
  - Friends and Relations - Lewis, L. W. - Use of Car, 1933-1935 (Box 78, Folder 591)
  - Friends and Relations - Leland, Bertha M., 1917-1933 (Box 78, Folder 592)
    Crank, convinced she was defrauded by Frank Rockefeller; tried to get money from John D. Rockefeller, Sr. and John D. Rockefeller, Jr.; accused John D. Rockefeller, Sr. of diabolical powers.
    108L32
  - Friends and Relations - Lennon, Patrick J., 1934-1959 (Box 78, Folder 593)
    Catholic priest at St. Cecilias Church, close friend of John D. Rockefeller, Sr.; John D. Rockefeller, Jr. gifts.
    108L33
  - Friends and Relations - Lindbergh, Charles A., 1927-1936 (Box 78, Folder 594)
    Tributes to him; flight with serum for Lloyd Bennett; China flight. Visits to Rockefeller home.
    108L5
  - Friends and Relations - Lindsey, Ben B., 1905-1940 (Box 78, Folder 595)
    Denver judge interested in child welfare; "tainted money" outcry over alleged offer of money by John D. Rockefeller, Sr.; comments on John D. Rockefeller, Jr.'s industrial plan.
  - Friends and Relations - Lloyd, Nellie, 1923-1925 (Box 78, Folder 596)
    John D. Rockefeller, Jr. guaranteed loan for church member in trucking business.
  - Friends and Relations - Link, Dr. Henry C., 1937-1952 (Box 78, Folder 597)
    Psychologist, poll-taker, wrote "Return to Religion;" John D. Rockefeller, Jr. interested.
    108L6
  - Friends and Relations - Larsen, Mrs. Lauritz, 1948-1954; Folder 1 of 2 (Box 78, Folder 598)
    Charlotte Larsen and husband were leaders in National Lutheran Council. John D. Rockefeller, Jr. gifts, pledge.
    108L7
  - Friends and Relations - Larsen, Mrs. Lauritz, 1955-1963; Folder 2 of 2 (Box 78, Folder 599)
  - Friends and Relations - McArthur, Edna, 1930-1940 (Box 79, Folder 600)
    Blind cousin of John D. Rockefeller, Jr. aided in costs of operation.
    108M1
  - Friends and Relations - McCarthy, Mr. and Mrs. Charles, 1917-1949; Folder 1 of 2 (Box 79, Folder 601)
    Social scientist, friend of John D. Rockefeller, Jr. at Brown. Small gifts. Tributes to career.
    108M11
  - Friends and Relations - McCarthy, Mr. and Mrs. Charles, 1898-1917; Folder 2 of 2 (Box 79, Folder 602)
  - Friends and Relations - McCormick, Mr. and Mrs. Cyrus, 1900-1936 (Box 79, Folder 603)
    Edith's father- and mother-in-law; request for loan; deaths.
    108M13
  - Friends and Relations - McCormick, Edith and Harold, 1906-1919; Folder 1 of 2 (Box 79, Folder 604)
    Edith to John D. Rockefeller, Jr., news from home in Cleveland and New York City. John D. Rockefeller, Jr. urged to confide in John D. Rockefeller, Sr. (1900); John D. Rockefeller, Sr. gifts to Edith for herself and family. No intimate family correspondence after 1902.
    108M14
  - Friends and Relations - McCormick, Edith and Harold, 1902-1909; Folder 2 of 2 (Box 79, Folder 605)
  - Friends and Relations - McCormick, Edith and Harold - Riverside Property, 1909-1917 (Box 79, Folder 606)
    Gift of land to Edith from John D. Rockefeller, Sr. - in Chicago.
  - Friends and Relations - McCormick, Edith Rockefeller, 1887-1905 (Box 79, Folder 607)
    John D. Rockefeller, Jr. correspondence with Edith regarding her affairs; financial difficulties. Her death. Accounts of her relations with Krenn and Dato. Changing values of Edith's estate.
  - Friends and Relations - McCormick, Edith Rockefeller - General, 1932-1957; Folder 1 of 2 (Box 80, Folder 608)
  - Friends and Relations - McCormick, Edith Rockefeller - General, 1925-1934; Folder 2 of 2 (Box 80, Folder 609)
  - Friends and Relations - McCormick, Edith Rockefeller, 1914-1921 (Box 80, Folder 610)
  - Friends and Relations - McCormick, Edith Rockefeller - Death and Estate, 1932-1933 (Box 80, Folder 611)
    Clippings.
  - Friends and Relations - McCormick, Edith Rockefeller, 1915-1921 (Box 80, Folder 612)
  - Friends and Relations - McCormick, Edith Rockefeller, 1917-1924 (Box 80, Folder 613)
  - Friends and Relations - McCormick, Edith Rockefeller - Gift of Standard Oil of New Jersey Stock, 1919-1920 (Box 80, Folder 614)
  - Friends and Relations - McCormick, Edith Rockefeller - Gertrude Hillenthal and Marie Pfaeffle, 1933-1952 (Box 80, Folder 615)
    Former employees got small pensions from John D. Rockefeller, Jr. after Edith's death.
  - Friends and Relations - McCormick, Edith Rockefeller - Letters Regarding Death, Illness, 1932 (Box 80, Folder 616)
  - Friends and Relations - McCormick, Edith Rockefeller - Trust, 1937 (Box 81, Folder 617)
  - Friends and Relations - McCormick, Edith Rockefeller, 1933-1944 (Box 81, Folder 618)
    Attempts to sell John D. Rockefeller, Jr. bonds of the Edith R. McCormick Trust declined.
  - Friends and Relations - McCormick, Edith Rockefeller - Trust, 1923-1934 (Box 81, Folder 619)
  - Friends and Relations - McCormick, Edith Rockefeller - Finances, 1917-1932 (Box 81, Folder 620)
    Chicago area real estate investments; development plans tied to trust fund. Failure of trust fund after real estate market collapse; threat of bankruptcy. John D. Rockefeller, Sr. and John D. Rockefeller, Jr. offers of assistance.
  - Friends and Relations - McCormick, Edith Rockefeller - Finances - Gifts, 1922-1933 (Box 81, Folder 621)
  - Friends and Relations - McCormick, Edith Rockefeller - Will, 1931-1933 (Box 81, Folder 622)
    Copies of 1931 and 1932 wills.
    108M14A
  - Friends and Relations - McCormick, Edith Rockefeller - Estate Settlement, 1932-1933; Folder 1 of 2 (Box 81, Folder 623)
    Disposition of trust funds among children; legal problems; rights of Krenn and Dato. Muriel's insistence on legal rights. Lawyers' discussion of issues. Mrs. Oser's neutral attitude.
  - Friends and Relations - McCormick, Edith Rockefeller - Estate Settlement, 1933-1948; Folder 2 of 2 (Box 81, Folder 624)
  - Friends and Relations - McCormick, Edith Rockefeller - Income Tax Returns Under Trust, 1932-1934 (Box 81, Folder 625)
  - Friends and Relations - McCormick, Edith Rockefeller - Trust and Estate Settlement, 1932-1934; Folder 1 of 4 (Box 81, Folder 626)
  - Friends and Relations - McCormick, Edith Rockefeller - Trust and Estate Settlement, 1934-1939; Folder 2 of 4 (Box 82, Folder 627)
  - Friends and Relations - McCormick, Edith Rockefeller - Trust Committee, 1941-1942 (Box 82, Folder 628)
    Committee of John D. Rockefeller, Jr., E. Prentice, Cyrus McCormick and their successors for management of 1917 trust fund established by John D. Rockefeller, Sr. for Edith. Discussion of financial needs of children, expenses charged to fund.
  - Friends and Relations - McCormick, Edith Rockefeller - Trust and Estate Settlement, 1917-1959; Folder 3 of 4 (Box 82, Folder 629)
  - Friends and Relations - McCormick, Edith Rockefeller - Trust and Estate Settlement - Resolutions, 1945-1961 (Box 82, Folder 630)
    Direction by Trust Committee to bank trustee to pay funds to Edith's children. Proxy powers; decisions on distribution of principal.
  - Friends and Relations - McCormick, Edith Rockefeller - Trust and Estate Settlement - Mathilde Oser, 1933-1943 (Box 82, Folder 631)
    Mrs. Oser's correspondence with John D. Rockefeller, Jr. and Trust Committee regarding her financial affairs and share in trust.
  - Friends and Relations - McCormick, Edith Rockefeller - Trust and Estate Settlement - Fowler McCormick, 1933-1944 (Box 82, Folder 632)
    Fowler's correspondence with John D. Rockefeller, Jr. and Trust Committee regarding his financial affairs and his share of trust fund.
  - Friends and Relations - McCormick, Edith Rockefeller - Trust and Estate Settlement - Fowler McCormick, 1939 (Box 82, Folder 0632A)
  - Friends and Relations - McCormick, Edith Rockefeller - Trust and Estate Settlement - Mrs. McKinlock, 1949-1956; Folder 1 of 2 (Box 82, Folder 633)
    Muriel McCormick's companion for 8 years; Muriel's gifts to her. Mrs. McKinlock's complaints about treatment.
  - Friends and Relations - McCormick, Edith Rockefeller - Trust and Estate Settlement - Mrs. McKinlock, 1954-1964; Folder 2 of 2 (Box 83, Folder 634)
  - Friends and Relations - McCormick, Edith Rockefeller - Trust and Estate Settlement - Mrs. McKinlock, 1959; Folder 2 of 2 (Box 83, Folder 0634A)
  - Friends and Relations - McCormick, Edith Rockefeller - Trust and Estate Settlement - Harrison Tweed, 1933-1937; Folder 1 of 3 (Box 83, Folder 635)
    Legal aspects of suit started by Muriel M. Hubbard; distribution of funds; legal fees. Memos on income taxes and trust management.
  - Friends and Relations - McCormick, Edith Rockefeller - Trust and Estate Settlement - Harrison Tweed, 1933-1944; Folder 2 of 3 (Box 83, Folder 636)
  - Friends and Relations - McCormick, Edith Rockefeller - Trust and Estate Settlement - Harrison Tweed, 1933-1936; Folder 3 of 3 (Box 83, Folder 637)
  - Friends and Relations - McCormick, Edith Rockefeller - Trust and Estate Settlement, 1959; Folder 4 of 4 (Box 83, Folder 638)
  - Friends and Relations - McCormick, Edith Rockefeller - Trust and Estate Settlement - Mrs. D. Hubbard, 1954-1960; Folder 1 of 2 (Box 83, Folder 639)
    Edith's daughter Muriel's dissatisfaction with arrangements after Edith's death; discussion of her objections; compromise. Her financial needs.
  - Friends and Relations - McCormick, Edith Rockefeller - Trust and Estate Settlement - Mrs. D. Hubbard, 1932-1940; Folder 2 of 2 (Box 84, Folder 640)
  - Friends and Relations - McCormick, Edith Rockefeller - Trust and Estate Settlement - Mrs. D. Hubbard - Trust for Children, 1943 (Box 84, Folder 641)
  - Friends and Relations - McCormick, Edith Rockefeller - Trust and Estate Settlement - Mrs. D. Hubbard - Trust, 1956-1964 (Box 84, Folder 642)
  - Friends and Relations - McCormick, Edith Rockefeller - Trust and Estate Settlement - Mrs. D. Hubbard - Trust, 1959-1964 (Box 84, Folder 0642A)
  - Friends and Relations - McCormick, Edith Rockefeller - Chase Suit Correspondence, 1933-1936 (Box 84, Folder 643)
    Referee held that principal of trust was not touched by Edith's will. Trust committee had full and vaild discretionary rights regarding principal; preparation for appeals. Legal fees.
    108M14B
  - Friends and Relations - McCormick, Edith Rockefeller - Chase Suit - Legal Documents, 1933; Folder 1 of 3 (Box 84, Folder 644)
    Printed briefs for hearings in New York Supreme Court and New York Supreme Court Appellate Division. Summons and Complaint. Minutes of Referee hearings; answers; summons.
  - Friends and Relations - McCormick, Edith Rockefeller - Chase Suit - Bound Legal Documents, 1933-1935; Folder 1 of 6 (Box 84, Folder 645)
  - Friends and Relations - McCormick, Edith Rockefeller - Chase Suit - Bound Legal Documents, 1933-1935; Folder 2 of 6 (Box 85, Folder 646)
  - Friends and Relations - McCormick, Edith Rockefeller - Chase Suit - Legal Documents, 1934; Folder 2 of 3 (Box 85, Folder 647)
  - Friends and Relations - McCormick, Edith Rockefeller - Chase Suit - Legal Documents, 1934; Folder 3 of 3 (Box 85, Folder 648)
  - Friends and Relations - McCormick, Edith Rockefeller - Chase Suit - Bound Legal Documents, 1933-1935; Folder 3 of 6 (Box 85, Folder 649)
  - Friends and Relations - McCormick, Edith Rockefeller - Chase Suit - Bound Legal Documents, 1933-1935; Folder 4 of 6 (Box 86, Folder 650)
  - Friends and Relations - McCormick, Edith Rockefeller - Chase Suit - Bound Legal Documents, 1933-1935; Folder 5 of 6 (Box 86, Folder 651)
  - Friends and Relations - McCormick, Edith Rockefeller - Chase Suit - Bound Legal Documents, 1933-1935; Folder 6 of 6 (Box 86, Folder 652)
  - Friends and Relations - McCormick, Edith Rockefeller - Litigation Expenses, 1936 (Box 86, Folder 653)
    Payment of lawyers.
  - Friends and Relations - McCormick, Edith Rockefeller - Chase Suit - Testimony, 1935-1936; Folder 1 of 2 (Box 86, Folder 654)
  - Not Used (Box 86, Folder 655)
  - Friends and Relations - McCormick, Edith Rockefeller - Chase Suit - Testimony, 1935-1936; Folder 2 of 2 (Box 87, Folder 656)
  - Friends and Relations - McCormick, Edith Rockefeller - John D. Rockefeller Deed of Trust - Equitable Suit - A. Oser, 1925-1926; Folder 1 of 2 (Box 87, Folder 657)
    Over proper distribution of stock dividends paid to Trust - Edith wanted them to be considered income; children and trustees want them considered principal - trustees tried to stay neutral. Settled out of court through compromise at John D. Rockefeller, Sr.'s suggestions; John D. Rockefeller, Sr. paid legal fees. Anita Oser, a co-plaintiff, represented by Harold McCormick. John D. Rockefeller, Jr.-Thomas M. Debevoise correspondence - plans for compromising suit. Printed briefs of Anita Oser's case in suit.
    108M14C
  - Friends and Relations - McCormick, Edith Rockefeller - John D. Rockefeller Deed of Trust - Equitable Suit - A. Oser, 1926-1929; Folder 2 of 2 (Box 87, Folder 658)
  - Friends and Relations - McCormick, Edith Rockefeller - John D. Rockefeller Deed of Trust - Equitable Suit - Gift of June 1927 (Box 87, Folder 659)
  - Friends and Relations - McCormick, Edith Rockefeller - John D. Rockefeller Deed of Trust - Equitable Suit - John D. Rockefeller, Sr./Jr. and Mr. Debevoise Correspondence, 1925-1927 (Box 87, Folder 660)
  - Friends and Relations - McCormick, Edith Rockefeller - Legal Papers, 1917-1927; Folder 1 of 4 (Box 88, Folder 661)
    Proposed Order with Notice of Settlement; Order with Notice of Entry; Answer; Notice of Motion and Affidavit; Notice of Motion for Reference and Affidavits; Notice of Hearing Before Referee with Summons; Notice of Appearance; Proposed Finds of Fact and Conclusions of Law; Requested Findings of Fact; Report of Referee on Separate Issues and Notice of Filing; Notice of Appeal; Notice of Argument; Opinion; Proposed Order with Notice of Settlement; Bill of Costs and Notice of Taxation; Judgement and Notice of Entry.
  - Friends and Relations - McCormick, Edith Rockefeller - Legal Papers, 1917-1927; Folder 2 of 4 (Box 88, Folder 662)
  - Friends and Relations - McCormick, Edith Rockefeller - Legal Papers, 1917-1927; Folder 3 of 4 (Box 88, Folder 663)
  - Friends and Relations - McCormick, Edith Rockefeller - Legal Papers, 1917-1927; Folder 4 of 4 (Box 88, Folder 664)
  - Friends and Relations - McCormick, Harold F. Jr. (Fowler), 1915-1924; Folder 1 of 3 (Box 89, Folder 665)
    John D. Rockefeller, Sr. grandson; his marriage, 1931.
    108M141
  - Friends and Relations - McCormick, Harold F. Jr. (Fowler), 1925-1958; Folder 2 of 3 (Box 89, Folder 666)
  - Friends and Relations - McCormick, Harold F. Jr. (Fowler), 1927; Folder 3 of 3 (Box 89, Folder 667)
  - Friends and Relations - McCormick, Mathilde (Oser), 1906-1960 (Box 89, Folder 668)
    John D. Rockefeller, Sr. granddaughter, died 1947. Marriages of her children Anita and Peter.
    108M142
  - Friends and Relations - McCormick, Muriel, 1922-1959; Folder 1 of 2 (Box 89, Folder 669)
    108M143
  - Friends and Relations - McCormick, Muriel, 1941; Folder 1 of 2 (Box 89, Folder 0669A)
  - Friends and Relations - McCormick, Muriel, 1921-1950; Folder 2 of 2 (Box 89, Folder 670)
  - Friends and Relations - McCormick, Muriel - Original Newspaper Clippings, 1944-1959 (Box 90, Folder 671)
  - Friends and Relations - McCormick, Muriel - Children Controversy, 1941-1954 (Box 90, Folder 672)
  - Friends and Relations - McKinlay, W. B., 1913-1949 (Box 90, Folder 673)
    Bible class student of Laura Spelman Rockefeller; small gifts from her. His ideas for investments, declined.
    108M146
  - Friends and Relations - Mampoteng, Fred, 1935-1948 (Box 90, Folder 674)
    Gardener at Pocantico Hills; financial troubles due to injuries; small loans and gifts.
    108M16
  - Friends and Relations - McVicar, Donald, 1926-1958 (Box 90, Folder 675)
    In charge of watchmen at Pocantico and 10 West 54th Street. Aid in purchasing land for dog kennels.
    108M17
  - Friends and Relations - McCrea, Mrs. Archibald, 1929-1960 (Box 90, Folder 676)
    Williamsburg friend of John D. Rockefeller, Jr. Death.
    108M18
  - Friends and Relations - Marston, E. L., 1916-1923 (Box 90, Folder 677)
    Friend of John D. Rockefeller, Sr.; Christmas greetings; investment offer.
  - Friends and Relations - Martin, H. L., 1913-1938 (Box 90, Folder 678)
    Seal Harbor resident employed by John D. Rockefeller, Jr. in office; left to work in brokerage firm. Business relations.
    108M19
  - Friends and Relations - Macy, V. Everett, 1913-1930 (Box 90, Folder 679)
    Commissioner of Public Welfare, Westchester; friend of John D. Rockefeller, Jr. John D. Rockefeller, Jr. speech at Cosmopolitan Club on Macy's wife.
    108M22
  - Friends and Relations - Macy Memorial, 1930-1953 (Box 91, Folder 680)
    Macy's death, 1930; John D. Rockefeller, Jr. interest in memorial, suggestions. Minutes of meetings of Memorial Committee.
  - Friends and Relations - Macy Memorial - Meetings of Memorial Committee, 1930-1932 (Box 91, Folder 681)
  - Friends and Relations - Macy Memorial - General Correspondence, 1930-1934 (Box 91, Folder 682)
  - Friends and Relations - Macy Memorial - Suggestions for Memorial, 1930-1931 (Box 91, Folder 683)
  - Friends and Relations - Marasco, Charles, 1929-1939 (Box 91, Folder 684)
    Tarrytown political leader; negotiations on zoning and road changes.
    108M23
  - Friends and Relations - Mansfield, Mrs. H., 1948-1959 (Box 91, Folder 685)
    Friend of Abby Aldrich Rockefeller. John D. Rockefeller, Jr. acted as donor so her art collection could be given to Yale. John D. Rockefeller, Jr. loan. Helen Mansfield's death, 1957.
    108M24
  - Friends and Relations - Mansfield, Mrs. H., 1954 (Box 91, Folder 685A)
  - Friends and Relations - Mansfield, Mrs. H. - Agreement Regarding Apartment, 1951-1958 (Box 91, Folder 686)
  - Friends and Relations - Mansfield, Mrs. H. - Agreement Regarding Apartment, 1956-1958 (Box 91, Folder 0686A)
  - Friends and Relations - Matteson, B. J., 1928-1957 (Box 91, Folder 687)
    Employee of Colorado Fuel and Iron Company (CF&I) retired, set up Texas fruit farm. John D. Rockefeller, Jr. gifts, loans.
    108M26
  - Friends and Relations - Mason, Charles B., 1901-1960 (Box 91, Folder 688)
    Employed in accounting office, 1901; pension, 1929, by John D. Rockefeller, Sr. and John D. Rockefeller, Jr. Death.
    108M27
  - Friends and Relations - Mayer, F. C., 1943-1959 (Box 92, Folder 689)
    John D. Rockefeller, Jr. gifts to West Point organist.
    108M28
  - Friends and Relations - Merritt, Hulett C., 1912-1951; Folder 1 of 2 (Box 92, Folder 690)
    Son of Lewis J. Merritt met John D. Rockefeller, Jr. while Director of Lake Superior Consolidated Mines, Mesabe Range. Friendly correspondence. Death, 1956.
    108M32
  - Friends and Relations - Merritt, Hulett C., 1951-1957; Folder 2 of 2 (Box 92, Folder 691)
  - Friends and Relations - Mercier, Cardinal, 1919-1926 (Box 92, Folder 692)
    Gift to Cardinal's fund for Belgian relief; tribute to Cardinal. His visit to Pocantico Hills.
    108M4
  - Friends and Relations - Miller, Lillian M., 1922-1934 (Box 92, Folder 693)
    Did wood block printing, met John D. Rockefeller, Jr. in Japan. Presents to John D. Rockefeller, Jr.; gifts to her during illness; purchase of prints for Riverside Church. Met Nelson A. Rockefeller and Mary C. Rockefeller on their honeymoon trip.
    108M44